[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
It's time for us to really sell
Salvador out here.
You will have your own show!
We just need to do
a makeover.
The controversies about the
demolition of Ginintuang Lupa,
I have no fault in that.
I want to pay back the favor
you did for my father.
I'm here to give financial aid.
If you came here
to buy us off...
You can't pay off
my father's hospitalization!
Leave!
What did you do
to the motorcycle?
He was about to pay for it!
We could've used that money
for your father's operation!
Don't worry. I'll get it back.
Use your beauty and charm.
Find out where
the motor parts are located.
I was hoping to ask
if you sell parts here.
For motorcycles.
Let's discuss it in our office.
Ah! Ah!
Gabo!
Come on, let's go!
- They're coming!
- I'll distract them!
Ahh!
He said...
I will have--
Just me.
I'll host my own show.
Wow! You're so great!
Oh my, I hope this develops!
You know, luckily,
I never regretted
having you as my partner!
You're so great!
- You're so talented!
- Salvador, Oli.
Give another report
against NLEA and Gen. Jacinto.
Okay? The audience loves that!
We have to make the most
of that issue, okay?
Alright, boss.
We'll find an interviewee
for the report.
Go to the place,
so we can feel the setting.
Focus on criticizing Jacinto.
Make it hot, feisty,
and, especially, dangerous.
Do it well, alright?
[STUTTERING] Wait, Salvador.
I thought you'll be hosting?
Why is he still asking you
to do field reports?
Never mind that.
We'll just report.
What matters is I have a job,
and you have a job too.
- That's right, Salvador.
- If you don't irritate me.
- Bingo! Okay.
- Let's go.
Thank you, thank you, Salvador.
[MANNY] Boss?
[CUTLERY CLINKS]
- Engr. Fernandez.
- Engr. Fernandez!
Welcome to my home,
and thank you for your interest.
I came here in a hurry
because I'm very interested
in your project.
Nice to hear.
Please, have a seat.
Thank you.
[CHAIR THUDS]
Tell me about your development.
It's Ginintuang Lupa, correct?
Well, let's say,
a development...
- by the sea...
- Mm-hmm.
But in the heart of Manila.
I mean, from that alone,
you can see the huge potential.
We're going to make it
a leisure hub,
so we plan to build
casinos, hotels,
condominiums, and malls.
And we'll make sure
that it's a...
...must-visit destination.
I'm really looking
to invest my money.
Thank you.
- That calls for a drink.
- It seems to early too drink.
Well, Engr. Fernandez, it's...
...5 o'clock somewhere
in this world.
[CHUCKLING]
Wait a minute.
Manny, let's give Mr. Gomez
- our best whiskey.
- Best whiskey! [CHUCKLES]
Well, boss? Is the list
of investors I gave you good?
- You're really dependable.
- Boss, you know,
if Mr. Gomez's money
comes in...
I'm certain we can start
the Phase 1 of the development.
Well, it looks like this is...
...my lucky day.
[CHUCKLING]
- [SALVADOR] Unbelievable!
- Sir.
- Harsh suffering was...
- Take a look.
...inflicted on the people
during the demolition
in Ginintuang Lupa.
And I found out
that the owner of the land
is General Ricardo Jacinto!
Is this real?
Looks like we're going
to have a problem.
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
I've been saving this bottle
for an occasion just like this.
[CORK POPS]
[ALCOHOL SLOSHING]
[BOTTLE THUDS]
Partner!
Maybe I should think twice
before calling you that.
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Uh, Engr. Fernandez,
just a while ago,
you were very interested.
I mean, what changed?
General Ricardo Jacinto!
Are you done with the people
from Ginintuang Lupa,
or just cooling off?
You law enforcers act
like you're demigods!
Let me spell it out, General,
in case you're slow to grasp.
You behave as if you were gods!
Back when you headed the NLEA,
abusive officers
were everywhere!
Are you truly enforcers
of the law,
or just power-trippers...
...flexing your muscles?
Is that what you want?
Then face me!
I challenge you!
Want to flaunt your strength?
Think you're strong?
Come on, let's settle this!
Check them out!
This is nothing.
Engineer, as you're well aware,
issues like this are a normal
part of any project.
How can you pull this off when
that's the sentiment toward you?
He's insulting you straight
to your face!
I can see it now.
This business venture will be
one headache after another.
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ENGINEER FERNANDEZ]
Thanks, anyway.
Maybe next time.
[FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
- [SLAMS TABLE]
- [SALVADOR] We'll fight back!
- Sir...
- General Ricardo--
- That reporter just won't quit.
- [SIGHS]
He's provoking us on purpose.
Does he think being part
of the media
gives him the right
to attack us?
I know General Jacinto.
If we're already boiling
with anger,
then he's definitely fuming.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Sir.
Maybe in this kind of situation,
we can wait for things
to cool down.
This will pass.
That's where
you're wrong, Umali.
General Jacinto is not
that kind of person.
[MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
Good job! [CHUCKLES]
- Could you open it?
- [DOOR SLIDING OPEN]
- Can you handle it?
- Yeah, I can.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
Wow. [CHUCKLES]
You know what, Salvador?
Honestly, I'm impressed.
That was gutsy of you.
Listen, Oli...
I just can't stand
abusive people.
Besides, the public needs
to see the truth.
[OLI] That's not it.
I think you can feel it now.
Your career is on the rise.
That's why your reporting is
burning with passion.
Forget it.
[CHUCKLES]
Me? Becoming a host?
[LIGHT MUSIC PLAYING]
That doesn't even feel real.
Just drop it.
Wait, wait. Didn't Boss Arnel
make that promise to you?
With Boss Arnel,
out of ten things he says,
eleven are wrong.
Sometimes even twelve.
There you go again.
You ended up this way
because you've been
in the company for years
without recognition.
So now you think, why would
they pay attention to you now?
- Right?
- You nailed it.
Of course I did.
Now, hang on.
Let's not forget something.
You followed my advice.
To show off in your reporting
to catch their attention.
That's how you'll get noticed.
Salvador, I'm sure of it.
I'm absolutely sure.
You'll have your own show.
Until it happens,
I won't believe it.
No way.
I'm the careful type.
Now, get in.
There you go again. Fine!
- Time to go.
- Let's get going.
[CAR DOOR SLIDING, CLOSES]
[OLI] Let's go, come on!
[DARK MUSIC PLAYING]
[GLASS THUDS]
[HUFFS]
[LINE RINGING]
[PHONE RINGING]
- General Jacinto.
- Domingo.
The Manila Telebalita reporter
is tearing my business apart.
[DARK MUSIC CONTINUES]
He's pushing it way too far.
Yes, sir.
That reporter is a real thorn
in the side.
You know what to do.
But Domingo...
you already messed up once.
Make sure it doesn't
happen again.
I won't mess this up,
General Jacinto.
I'm going to mobilize our men.
You can count--
[PHONE BEEPS]
[LINE DROPPED]
[DARK MUSIC CONTINUES]
We need to act now.
Round up the henchmen.
What's the plan, sir?
We're going to silence
Salvador's mouth.
Remember, failure is
not an option.
Or else, General Jacinto
will have our heads.
Sir.
Paquito and Django are reliable.
The next time I speak
with General Jacinto,
he must be pleased
with the news I bring him.
- Yes, sir!
- Yes, sir.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[ISOBEL] Oh, Ricardo.
I saw Engineer
Fernandez was here.
What happened? Were you able
to close the deal?
Did you negotiate with him?
- He backed out.
- What?
What did you do?
Remember the reporter
who always has something to say?
Well, Fernandez saw his report.
He got scared
of the negative publicity.
Oh my gosh!
I'm getting worried
about Ginintuang Lupa.
If we sit and don't do anything,
this problem
might become bigger.
I already took care of it,
Isobel.
I'm going to teach
Salvador a lesson.
Oh, no.
Ricardo, don't do that.
If you do, then your plan
might become a bigger issue.
Whatever happens to him...
happened because
he asked for it!
Let this serve as a lesson
to the media industry
to think before they attack me.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING, FADES]
Families like that
are really something.
- They're money-hungry.
- [UMALI] Jacinto!
[SIGHS]
- [MAX] Sir.
- [CHUCKLES]
Why aren't you wearing
your uniform?
Are you off duty?
Oh, we went to Ginintuang Lupa.
Colonel Domingo asked us
to sort out something.
You went to Ginintuang Lupa
without telling me?
I could've gone with you
so we could protect
the police station's princess!
Princess?
Sir, I am a cop.
I can protect myself.
Ah, you're wearing civilian
clothes too, sir.
Where are you going?
Oh, it's nothing.
- Just a routine check.
- Here.
Have you seen this?
[SALVADOR] General
Ricardo Jacinto!
Will you finally stop bothering
the people in Ginintuang Lupa?
Or are you just
clearing your head?
- [MAX] That's slander!
- Law enforcers!
Just because he stands
with the poor
doesn't mean he can paint
my father as the villain.
Don't be stressed.
Let's let this situation
cool down first.
He'll eventually stop babbling.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Excuse me, sir.
[ESTRELLA] Excuse me.
Here.
[PAQUITO] Come eat with me.
I don't want to.
I'm still full.
Are you still jealous
of Betchay, Ibyang?
Why would I be jealous?
I'm obviously younger
and more beautiful than her!
Paquito won't leave you
over Betchay!
He better not!
Let me remind you, Paquito.
I have made a lot
of sacrifices in this business.
And you'll just let
Betchay work there?
Their family is the plague
to our business!
Ibyang.
How many times
do I have to explain
that Betchay is useful?
I'll use her against
Rudy and Gabo.
- So we can finally beat them.
- Oh gosh!
I want that woman
out of BeerGin!
I don't want her to work there!
I'll think about it.
What do you mean?
It's a very easy decision!
[OBJECTS CLATTERS]
[ROMY] Here's my advice,
brother.
- Go ahead.
- Listen to her or you might...
Well... Betchay
still has some sex appeal.
[ROMY] Here's what
I'm curious about, Paquito.
Out of all the places
to apply from,
- she decided on BeerGin.
- Well...
She's desperate.
She had no other choice.
[ROMY] What's the update
on Rudy?
I heard he's
in critical condition.
He hasn't woken up until now.
If I were Betchay,
I'd give up on Rudy.
Look at her now.
She'll be in so much dept
and then what?
He dies anyway.
- Tell me, am I wrong?
- [KNIFE CLATTERS]
It's the truth.
Let me tell you this,
with poor people like us,
when one of us gets sick,
that means only
a 50% chance of surviving.
And then we die eventually.
Am I right?
Why do you seem
so concerned about Betchay?
Oh please, Ibyang,
quit nagging.
Don't make me angry.
What?
Hey, are you trying to kill me
with that much chili?
That's too much.
I hope it makes
your stomach hurt.
- She still got it, right?
- Definitely.
I'm still here, you know!
I can hear you!
Hey, we're just kidding!
[PLATE CLANKS]
[KID] Boss Django! Boss Django!
Here's all we got.
- Give it to Udo. Udo!
- [UDO] Come here.
[BOTTLES CLINK]
Boss Django,
these are our recruits.
Where did you find those?
At the dump yard.
They're new in the area.
[LIQUID TRICKLES]
[SPLAT]
What are your names?
- I'm Boybits, boss.
- I'm Pulong.
I'm Kanor, boss.
I'm Ador, boss.
I'm Hector, boss.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
Are you guys good at fighting?
They're great, boss.
They're used to
neighborhood fights.
I didn't ask you.
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [MEN GRUNTING]
[GUN COCKS]
[MUSIC TURNS SOMBER]
[LAUGHS MOCKINGLY]
That's what I'm looking for.
Someone strong.
Listen up.
We have a few rules around here.
First,
you must obey all of my orders.
And my Pa's too, Paquito.
We are the bosses here.
Second,
you need to put money
on the table.
I don't care how you do it.
What matters is that
you keep money coming in here.
Do you understand?!
- Yes, boss!
Good.
Boss Paquito.
- Pa.
- Oh, Django.
These are our recruits.
They're strong.
We can use them in operations
while Topak is in jail.
Aside from being strong
and brave,
you must also
do the job cleanly.
We don't want to get in trouble.
Do you understand?
- Yes, boss!
I got this, Pa.
I'll train them.
I'll let them tag along with me.
Alright. That's good, Django.
Get your men ready,
so when you cross paths
with Gabo,
we won't lose again.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello?
- Let's meet in your area.
Where?
Where do we always meet?
Do I need to remind you
where it is?
The usual spot!
Hurry up!
I'm on my way.
Umali wants to talk to us.
Why?
He didn't say,
but it seems important.
Come on. Let's not make
our guest wait.
Give me my shirt.
[MUSIC TURNS TENSE]
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
This guy's name is Umali.
He's the one
who gives us jobs.
[PAQUITO CLEARS THROAT]
They're here.
[SNICKERS] You've got some nerve
to come here, don't you think?
Did you forget you're part
of the demolition team?!
Django.
Calm down.
Let's listen
to what they have to say.
So that's what
you're angry about, Django.
That's it? Did the demolition
go as planned?
Not for now!
And then what?!
You're thinking far ahead.
Don't worry about it for now.
I'm not thinking far ahead!
I just want to know now...
what side you're choosing
when all hell breaks loose.
Is it with your bosses,
the higher-ups,
or with us who brings you money?
Django.
We'll side with those
who we can benefit more from.
Do you understand?
Umali...
If that unfortunate day
happens again,
I hope we all do
the right thing.
We don't want
to blame each other in the end.
And why did you ask us
to come here?
The keywords
are cool and mainstream.
- Boss, boss.
- Oh, Salvador.
You're here.
What's going on, boss?
Oh, come on!
In an hour, we'll do a look test
for your makeover.
Salvador, you're a big shot now!
They hired a whole team
for your makeover!
That's fantastic, man!
For what?
For your new show!
Goodness. Just go.
Makeup! Makeup, Salvador!
Come on, sit. Sit down.
Hold on.
[SPRITZING]
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Wow! Man, you look good!
That's bitter.
Wear these.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
Salvador!
[CHUCKLES, CLAPS]
What does it feel like
to be a star?
Tell me, man,
are you having fun?
I'm still a reporter.
I'm just wearing fancy clothes.
If anything, I'm a starlet.
Whether it be
a starlet, starfish,
or star apple,
you're still a star, man.
You've always been this way,
doubting yourself.
Do you see all of that?
That's all for you, man.
If you think
you don't have potential,
then why did they bother
doing all of this?
Well, you're right.
It's nice...
to know that the stories
you tell matter.
[CHUCKLES] Of course.
We're partners, remember?
I have a job for you.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[PAPER RUSTLES]
Hmm.
Just like before?
You want him killed?
Not really.
Just scare him.
Let's just kill him.
It'd be easier.
Don't.
That reporter
always targets our station.
We're always in his news scoop.
He thinks we shot the man
during the demolition.
If something happens to him,
they'll suspect no one but us.
You could make it look like
a robbery incident.
He fought back
that's why he got beaten up.
Or stabbed.
Or it could be...
he got shot.
But don't shoot him dead.
The goal is to keep
that bastard's mouth shut.
Here's the downpayment.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Make sure
to get the job done cleanly.
Of course. [SNICKERS]
You've got it, Umali.
We'll take care of this.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Uncle, how is Papa?
Still the same.
Have you seen the bike?
It would be a waste
if you lost that.
What now, Gabo?
Didn't you promise
that you're going to
solve that problem?
Don't worry.
I got the bike.
Oh, that's a relief.
The owner can reclaim
their bike.
Rudy can finally
undergo surgery.
Finally,
you have some good news for us.
A break from all the problems
you've caused us.
[MAMENG] Oh my gosh, Betchay.
Come on, Betchay.
I wonder if there
will ever be a day
when I'll get to say that
you're not being a buzzkill.
How is it my fault again?
- Just shush.
- That's enough.
You're giving me a headache.
Go on, Gabo.
Go see your father.
- [EKG MACHINE BEEPING]
- [SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
- [SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [BEEPING CONTINUES]
- [EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY]
- [RUDY GRUNTING]
Pa! Pa!
Doc! Doc, help! Help!
Pa...
Pa! Pa!
- Excuse me, sir.
- Pa! Pa!
- Rudy! Rudy! Rudy!
- Pa. Pa! Pa!
Doc, please do everything
to save my father!
- [BETCHAY SOBBING]
- Pa! Pa!
- Gabo! What happened?!
- Pa! Pa...
- Rudy!
- Pa!
Pa!
[MAMENG] Gabo, come here!
Pa! Pa!
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Pa!
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
He should find a way
to help save his father's life.
What do you need, Gabo?
Please help me.
I need money.
If we don't move now,
we won't have another chance.
This case is personal to me now.
I'm not going to stop until
Tiger is held accountable.
That's Samantha Jacinto.
She was the one who arrested
my brother.
I'll take care of her myself.
There are a lot of eyes
watching us.
We need to be careful
so our plan won't fail.
I know that you need my help
because your father
is in the hospital
and is in a critical condition.
You need to get the gold
from Mr. Chan,
whether he's dead or alive.
We will arrest Mr. Chan.
This time, we won't let him
get away.